Homepage: https://starsuzi.github.io Email: starsuzi@kaist.ac.kr Google Scholar: /Soyeong Jeong

RESEARCH **INTEREST**

My research interests are mainly on information retrieval for solving open domain language tasks and interpretation of large language models for making them interpretable when deployed on real-world applications. Not limited to, I am interested in broad topics on natural language understanding.

EDUCATION

KAIST Daejeon, Korea Mar 2022 - Present Ph.D. in School of Computing M.S. in School of Computing Mar 2020 - Feb 2022

Thesis: Information Retrieval by Augmenting Document Representation

Seoul, Korea **Korea University**

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Graduated with Honor)

B.E. in Software Technology and Enterprise Program (Interdisciplinary Program)

Anyang Foreign Language High School

Anyang, Korea Mar 2013 - Feb 2016 Prestigious high school for talented students (Major in English)

EMPLOYMENT

Graduate student, KAIST (Advisor: Prof. Jong Cheol Park)

Mar 2020 - Present

Mar 2016 - Feb 2020

- Conducted research on investigating the self-adaptive capabilities of smaller instruction fine-tuned LMs.
- Conducted research on the open conversational question-answering task.
- · Conducted research on augmentation of both sparse and dense retrievers by expanding the document texts and their representations.
- Conducted research on interpreting pre-trained language models based on calibration.

Mar 2019 - Feb 2020 Undergrad. Research Assistant, Korea University (Advisor: Prof. Jaewoo Kang)

- Participated in the major recommendation project by embedding curriculum vectors.
- Participated in the food ingredient & drug graph construction project.

Research Intern, Seoul SW-SoC Convergence R&BD Center, ETRI

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

· Participated in the Speech Emotion Recognition project and developed a neural network architecture to classify emotions from the input voice.

Research Intern, Artificial Intelligence Research Laboratory, ETRI

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

· Participated in the AIR project (Developing Artificial Social Intelligence for Human-Care Robots) and developed a web crawler for gathering, annotating, and analyzing images and metadata.

PUBLICATIONS

International Publications

- [18] Adaptive-RAG: Learning to Adapt Retrieval-Augmented Large Language Models through Question Complexity Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, Sukmin Cho, Sung Ju Hwang, and Jong C. Park North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL), 2024
- [17] Test-Time Self-Adaptive Small Language Models for Question Answering Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, Sukmin Cho, Sung Ju Hwang, and Jong C. Park Findings of the Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (Findings of EMNLP), 2023
- [16] Knowledge-Augmented Language Model Verification Jinheon Baek, Soyeong Jeong, Minki Kang, Jong C. Park, and Sung Ju Hwang Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2023
- [15] Improving Zero-shot Reader by Reducing Distractions from Irrelevant Documents in Open-Domain Question Answering Sukmin Cho, Jeongyeon Seo, Soyeong Jeong, Jong C. Park Findings of the Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (Findings of EMNLP), 2023
- [14] Phrase Retrieval for Open-Domain Conversational Question Answering with Conversational Dependency Modeling via Contrastive Learning Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, Sung Ju Hwang, and Jong C. Park Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Findings of ACL), 2023

- [13] Discrete Prompt Optimization via Constrained Generation for Zero-shot Re-ranker Sukmin Cho, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Jeong yeon Seo, Jong C. Park Findings of Association for Computational Linguistics (Findings of ACL), 2023.
- [12] Realistic Conversational Question Answering with Answer Selection based on Calibrated Confidence and Uncertainty Measurement <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Jinheon Baek, Sung Ju Hwang, and Jong C. Park Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL), 2023
- [11] Augmenting Document Representations for Dense Retrieval with Interpolation and Perturbation Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, Sukmin Cho, Sung Ju Hwang, and Jong C. Park Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2022 (Oral)
- [10] Query Generation with External Knowledge for Dense Retrieval Sukmin Cho, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Wonsuk Yang, Jong C. Park Deep Learning Inside Out at Association for Computational Linguistics (**DeeLIO @ ACL**), 2022.
- [9] Unsupervised Document Expansion for Information Retrieval with Stochastic Text Generation Soyeong Jeong, Jinheon Baek, ChaeHun Park, and Jong C. Park Scholarly Document Processing Workshop at NAACL (SDP @ NAACL), 2021 (Oral)
- [8] Development of Speech Emotion Recognition Algorithm using MFCC and Prosody Hyejin Koo, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Sungjae Yoon, Wonjong Kim International Conference on Electronics, Information, and Communication (ICEIC), 2020.

Domestic Publications, mostly written in Korean

- [7] Controllable prompt tuning with relation dependent tokens Jinseok Kim, Sukmin Cho, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, and Jong C. Park Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2023.
- [6] Stopwords Mask Pooling for Dense Retrieval in Medical Domain Dongho Choi, Hoyun Song, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Sukmin Cho, and Jong C. Park Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2022. (Best Presentation)
- [5] Assessing automatic summarization model as a reading assistant Aujin Kim, Jisu Shin, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Sukmin Cho, and Jong C. Park Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2022.
- [4] Calibration of Pre-trained Language Model for the Korean Language Soyeong Jeong, Wonsuk Yang, ChaeHun Park, Jong C. Park Journal of KIISE (JOK), 2021.
- [3] Calibration of Pre-trained Language Model for Korean Soyeong Jeong, Wonsuk Yang, ChaeHun Park, Jong C. Park Human & Cognitive Language Technology (HCLT), 2020. (Best Paper)
- [2] Embedding Academic Majors and Lectures for Analyzing Departments in University Jinheon Baek, Gwanghoon Jang, <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>, Donghyeon Park, Kiwon Kwon, Jaewoo Kang Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2019.

Thesis

 Information Retrieval by Augmenting Document Representation <u>Soyeong Jeong</u>
 Master's Thesis, KAIST, 2022

Honors and Awards

Awarded a Ph.D. fellowship from NRF (National Research Foundation) of Korea	2023
Title: Realistic Open-domain Question Answering System with Large Language Models	
Received the Best Paper Award at HCLT 2020	2020
Graduated with Honor	2019
Computer Science and Engineering Department at Korea University	
Received the First Prize in the Graduation Project, Competition Among Around 20 Teams	2019
Computer Science and Engineering Department at Korea University	
Nominated as Semester High Honors (Spring 2019)	2019
Nominated as Semester High Honors (Fall 2018)	2018

	Received the Second Prize for the iOS Hackathon at Korea University Awarded as the Finalist, Competition of 21:1 with 735 total submissions LG Global Challenger	2018 2017
Academic	Reviewer of ACL ARR 2024 February Reviewer	2023
Services	Reviewer of ACL ARR 2023 October, December Reviewer	2023
	Reviewer of TALLIP 2022 (ACM Transactions on Asian and Low-Resource Language Information Processing)	2022
	Reviewer of ACL-IJCNLP Demo Track 2021	2021
Teaching	Computational Linguistics (CS579) KAIST Fall 2022 (Teaching Assistant)	
	Natural Language Processing with Python (CS372)	
	KAIST Spring 2020, Spring 2021, Spring 2023 (Teaching Assistant)	
Skills	Languages: Korean (mother tongue), English (fluent)	
	Programming: Python, C, Java, Swift	